Derek Ouach

🛮 206-372-4149 | 💌 derek.quach15@gmail.com | 🖸 dnqUW | 🛅 derek-quach-4b69a51aa/ | Portfolio

Personal Profile

Technical writer with 1.5 years, software development of 4 years, IT tech of 2 years, and 5+ years writing for target audiences. English BA & Bio AA. Excellent: project management, programming, SEO/keyword research, verbal and writing skills. Has experience and familar with SSO, SDLC, REST API, JSON. Works WELL with developers, SMEs, software, and SSO in sprints.

Skills

Programming Java, SQL, Markdown, HTML, CSS, JScript, Git, GitHub, (Click here for Certifications)

· 100% completion & score on all assignments and labs. SQL queries, Big O, data structures, algorithms.

Technical Writing, Concise documentation, APIs, Java, SQL, HTML, JScript, Oxygen XML, Madcap Flare, Confluence, MS Suite, **Technical**

Adobe suite, Yoast SEO, Microsoft suite, DaVinci Resolve, Data structures, Algorithms, Figma

Soft Skills Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Friendly, Engaging Presentation.

Work Experience _____

Revature Reston, VA

Bootcamp Software Engineer

• Aced all 93 (combined) Java and SQL coding labs, challenges, and mini-projects

• Developed social media API application and corresponding technical documentation

humanID Cambridge, MA

Technical Writing Team Lead 2022 - 2023

· Maintained all tech writing standard operating procedures, tutorials, training manuals, and field documentation of our SaaS login

• Expanded blog's article count for technical audiences by 10% and optimized SEO score and web traffic by 15%

· Instructed and delegated over 50 technical writing tasks and tracked three onboarding processes single-handedly

Cambridge, MA Technical Writing Intern 2022 - 2023

23% augmentation rate domain authority. Suitability for general audience average score from 80% to 90%

Utilized graphics to supplement clear and concise documentation. Surpassed expected quantity of deliverables

• Slashed documentation delivery time by 25% while working with software engineers & SME team

TQComputers INC. Burien, WA

IT Technician 2018 - 2020

Over 80 walk-in clients' devices (Windows laptops, desktops, printers & iOS tablets) restored to the desired functionality

Researched, evaluated and recommended resolutions to business owners and end users

Education

humanID

University of Washington

Seattle, WA

May 2023 - Sept 2023

Bachelor of Arts: English

Highline College Des Moines, WA

Associate of Science: Biology

Current Projects

How to Build a Neural Network

Self-interest Dec 2023 - Present

• Over 55 hours spent learning neural networks

- Java and python used as different methods to creating the neural network
- Flappy Bird used as an example
- Technical Skills: Machine Learning, AI, Neural Networks, Backward Propogation.

The OSI 7-Layer Model: IT Fundamentals

Self-interest Mar 2024 - Present

- Over 15 hours spent learning about the OSI model.
- Technical Skills: IT fundamentals, OSI model.

MARCH 12, 2024